Guide to the Papers of Robert B. McKay 1919-1990 MC.208
New York University Archives
- Series I., 32332
  - Conference of Chief Justices Coordinating Council on Lawyer Competence, 1985; 32584 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - TORT Reform: What's on the Horizon?, 1988; 32583 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Speeches and Correspondence, 1984-1990; 32582 (Box 25)
  - ADR Teaching Correspondence Teaching and Materials, 1989-1990; 32581 (Box 26)
  - Campaign Finance Board - Clippings, 1989; 32580 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Campaign Finance Board - Clippings, 1989; 32579 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Campaign Finance Board - Clippings, 1989; 32578 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - NYC Campaign Finance Board, 1988-1990; 32577 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - NYC Campaign Finance Board, 1988-1990; 32576 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - NYC Campaign Finance Board, 1988-1990; 32575 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - NYC Campaign Finance Board, 1988-1990; 32574 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - NYC Campaign Finance Board, 1988-1990; 32573 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Emory Law Journal, 1980; 32572 (Box 27)
  - Tel Aviv University Studies in Law, 1980; 32571 (Box 27)
  - Private Investors Abroad, 1986; 32570 (Box 27)
  - McKay Publications, Articles, Journals, 1966-1990; 32569 (Box 28)
  - RBM - Speechs and Manuscripts, 1975; 32568 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Materials on State of Justice Paper, 1976; 32567 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Speechs and Manuscripts, 1975; 32566 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Speechs and Manuscripts, 1975; 32565 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Speechs and Manuscripts, 1975; 32564 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - MAFCOTE Industries, undated; 32563 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Citizens Union, undated; 32562 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Ethics and Values Colloquium, undated; 32561 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - New York City Parks Commission, undated; 32560 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - New York City Parks Commission, undated; 32559 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - New York City Parks Commission, undated; 32558 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Offices of Lawyers Professional Responsibility, undated; 32557 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - National Judicial College - Board of Directors Meeting, July 12-14 1990, Reno NV, 32556 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Aspen Institute, 1920-1999; 32555 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Legal Aid Society, 1986; 32554 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Michael Rose, undated; 32553 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - HALT, 1990; 32552 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - NJC Long-Range Plan, 1990; 32551 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - ABA TIPS TORT law and the public interest, 1920-1999; 32550 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Summary of Bar Council, 1990; 32549 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - ABA Long Range Planning Committee, 1988; 32548 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - NYU Law Schoool Debt Burden, 1988; 32547 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Misc. Papers on the Legal Profession, 1988-1990; 32546 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Prof Res. Conf., 1990; 32545 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - CPR Legal Program, undated; 32544 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Manville Insurance, 1988; 32543 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - NYU Humanities Council, 1983; 32542 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Fall 1982 LO 9.3522, 32541 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - McGeorge School of Law, 1983; 32540 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Reimbursements RBM, 1980-1983; 32539 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - University of San Diego, 1983; 32538 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Tulsa University Speech, 1981-05-10; 32537 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Criminal Justice Panel, 1979-1983; 32536 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - University of Kansas, 1983; 32535 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - LCF Nominating Committee, 1982-1985; 32534 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Law School Admissions Council, 1983; 32533 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Loews Corporation, 1986; 32532 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Manville, 1987; 32531 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Torts Reform, 1987; 32530 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, undated; 32529 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Tort Reform Commission, 1985-1987; 32528 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Manville, 1987; 32527 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Institute for Civil Justice, 1985-1986; 32526 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Miscellanous, 1984-1986; 32525 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Manville, 1987; 32524 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Goldstein vs. Goldstein, 1989; 32523 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - State Bar Discipline Monitor, undated; 32522 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Task Force on Law Schools, undated; 32521 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - TIPS, undated; 32520 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - TIPS, undated; 32519 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - TIPS, undated; 32518 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Task Force on Law Schools, undated; 32517 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Task Force on Law Schools, undated; 32516 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Task Force on Law Schools, undated; 32515 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - McKay Writings, 1958; 32514 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - McKay Writings, 1965; 32513 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - McKay Writings, 1972; 32504 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - McKay Writings, 1955; 32503 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - McKay Writings, 1969; 32502 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Assorted Journals with McKay Articles, 1965; 32501 (Box 33)
  - CPR Legal Program (ADR), 1990; 32500 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - ADR Conference / Articles, 1982; 32499 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - ADR Conference / Articles, 1988; 32498 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1958; 32497 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Let's Talk Law - Scripts, undated; 32496 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Dispute Resolution Center, 1983; 32495 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Criminal Justice / Legal Education, 1981; 32494 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - AALS / NALP Committee on Placement, 1988; 32493 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - AALS Notre Dame Inspection, 1988; 32492 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Puerto Rican Legal Defense Fund, 1987; 32491 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Miami Valley Paper Co., undated; 32490 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - ABA Graduate Legal Education Committee, 1978; 32489 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Judicial / Administration Seminar, 1981; 32488 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - ABA Special Committee on Products Liability, 1983; 32487 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - McKay Writings, 1958; 32486 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Journals / Newsletters, 1972; 32485 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Conferences, 1984; 32484 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Reports / Plans / Recommendations, 1982; 32483 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Articles / Journals, 1960; 32482 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Brigham Young University Law Review, 1977; 32481 (Box 34)
  - National Judicial College (NJC), 1990; 32480 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1986; 32479 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - ABCNY (Association of the Bar of the City of New York), 1990; 32478 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Annual Judicial Conference, 1985; 32477 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - National Judicial College, 1990; 32476 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - SALT (Society of American Law Teachers), 1990; 32475 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1978; 32474 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Supreme Court - Report of the Special Master (Georgia v. S. Carolina), 1988; 32473 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Volunteers of Legal Services, 1990; 32472 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - MALDEF (Mexican American Legal Defense and Educational Fund), 1990; 32471 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Revson Foundation, 1990; 32470 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1976-1979; 32469 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1976-1978; 32468 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - NY State Bar, 1989; 32467 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Legal Aid, 1989; 32466 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Philadelphia Police Study Task Force, undated; 32465 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Loews, 1989; 32464 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Fund for Modern Courts, 1990; 32463 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Manville Trust, 1990; 32462 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1976-1979; 32461 (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Misc., 1990; 32460 (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1977-1978; 32459 (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1975-1978; 32458 (Box 35, Folder 23)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1978-1979; 32457 (Box 35, Folder 24)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1975-1978; 32456 (Box 35, Folder 25)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1977-1979; 32455 (Box 35, Folder 26)
  - Clippings and Article, 1987-1988; 32454 (Box 35, Folder 27)
  - Citizens Union, 1988-1990; 32453 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Citizens Union, 1989; 32452 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Citizens Union, 1987-1990; 32451 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Citizens Union, 1986-1989; 32450 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Citizens Union, 1986-1989; 32449 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Tarabishi vs. McAlester Regional Hospital (binder), 1983-1984; 32448 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Legal Aid Society, 1984-1985; 32447 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Legal Education/Professional Competence, 1980-1988; 32446 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Professional Independence of the Lawyer, 1984; 32445 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Legal Education/Professional Competence, 1980-1983; 32444 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Mandatory Continuing Legal Education, 1987-1990; 32443 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Mandatory Continuing Legal Education, 1987-1989; 32442 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Mandatory Continuing Legal Education, 1981-1988; 32441 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Goldstein vs. Goldstein, 1988; 32440 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Goldstein vs. Goldstein, 1988; 32439 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - University of Iowa Fall 1983, 32438 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Commission on Professionalism, 1985; 32437 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - ABA Lawyer Discipline, 1988-1989; 32436 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - ABA TIPS Long Range Planning, 1988; 32435 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - ABA Young Lawyers Division, 1988; 32434 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - California Lawyer Discipline, 1988-1989; 32433 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Property and Casualty Insurance: Fact or Fantasy?, 1989; 32432 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Written Testimony Vol II, 1990; 32431 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Product Liability, 1990; 32430 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - The Electoral Process in the U.S., 1988; 32429 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Outline Manual for Mass Tort Litigation, undated; 32428 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Synar vs. United States of America, 1986; 32427 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Legal Aid Society Sentencing Guideline Cases, 1988; 32426 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - In Re Sealed Case ABA Amicus Curiae Brief, 1987; 32425 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Seperation of Powers Personal Notes, 1986; 32424 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - ABA Commission on Evaluation of Disciplinary Enforcement, 1990; 32423 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Commission on Evaluation of Disciplinary Enforcement - Written Testimony, 1990; 32422 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - ABA Commission on Evaluation of Disciplinary Enforcement, 1990; 32421 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - ABA Commission on Evaluation of Disciplinary Enforcement, 1990; 32420 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - ABA TIPS Professional Independence…Commission, 1987-1988; 32419 (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - ABA, 1987-1990; 32418 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Cases and Materials on Affirmative Action, 1979-1983; 32417 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Misc. materials on professional responsibility and ethics, 1986-1990; 32416 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - American Law Institute Restatement of the Law, 1989; 32415 (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - NYS Committee to Improve the Availability of Legal Services, 1988-1989; 32414 (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - NYSBA Committee on Professional Discipline Seminar, 1990; 32413 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - ABA TIPS Federal Product Liability, 1989; 32412 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - TORT Reform, 1989; 32411 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1990; 32410 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Civil Liberties Program - Yale, 1985; 32409 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Judicial Administration Class Syllabus, 1982; 32408 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - TIPS, 1984-1986; 32407 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - ABA/TIPS Task Force on Referenda, 1989; 32406 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Misc. ABA Correspondence, 1990; 32405 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Misc. ADR, 1987-1990; 32404 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Misc. ADR, 1989-1990; 32403 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Misc. ABA, 1990; 32402 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Misc. NYSBA, 1990; 32401 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Aspen Institute, 1984; 32400 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Philadelphia Police, 1983-1989; 32399 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Attica, 1983; 32398 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Lotteries, 1985-1990; 32397 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - A Student's Guide to Mediation and the Law, 1987; 32396 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Alternative Dispute Resolution Seminar, 1988; 32395 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Published Materials, 1985; 32394 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - NYU: Teaching, 1989; 32393 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Conflict Management Training Guide, 1988; 32392 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - State Ethics Commission - Meeting of June 2, 1988, 32391 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - State Ethics Commission, 1988; 32390 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Ethical Considerations in ADR by Robert McKay, undated; 32389 (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - ABA Product Liability Hearings, 1990; 32388 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - ABA Product Liability Hearings, 1990; 32387 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - ABA Commission on Evaluation of Disciplinary Enforcement, 1989; 32386 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Published Materials, 1985-1989; 32385 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - ABA Correspondence, 1989; 32384 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - ABA Special Coordinating Committee on Professionalism, 1989; 32383 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - ABA Special Coordinating Committee on Professionalism, 1989-1990; 32382 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Constitutional Adjudication in a Presidential System of Government, undated; 32381 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Virtue, Commerce and Lawyers, undated; 32380 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Misc. Materials on Lawyer Competence, 1987-1990; 32379 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - NYSBA Special Committee…Pro Bono Service, 1989; 32378 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - ABA Consortium on Professional Competence, 1985; 32377 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - ABA Conference on Professionalism, Ethics and Economic Change, 1988; 32376 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Misc. Materials on Reapportionment, 1984; 32375 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Bakke and Beyond Articles, 1978; 32374 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Bakke Related Issues, 1975-1978; 32373 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1978-1979; 32372 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Regents of UC v. Bakke, 1977-1978; 32371 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1977-1979; 32370 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1977; 32369 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Affirmative Action: Minority Enrollment, 1977; 32368 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Affirmative Action Clippings, 1977; 32367 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1977; 32366 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1976-1978; 32365 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1975-1977; 32364 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1977-1978; 32363 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Black Students in Higher Education - Judy Roizen, undated; 32362 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1977-1978; 32361 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Minority Education - Ford Foundation, 1976-1977; 32360 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Law School Admissions Research, 1974-1976; 32359 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1973-1978; 32358 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1976; 32357 (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1977; 32356 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1976-1977; 32355 (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1976; 32354 (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1978-1979; 32353 (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Affirmative Action: Bakke, 1974-1978; 32352 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Coordinating Council on Professional Competence, 1983; 32351 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Judicial Education on International Law (Judge Re), 1983; 32350 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Kutak Commission, 1979-1983; 32349 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - American Judicature Society, 1982-1983; 32348 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Citizens Union Research Foundation, 1982-1983; 32347 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Cromwell Dinner, 1977-1983; 32346 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Democracy Project, 1983; 32345 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - William O'Douglas Inquiry Paper, 1981-1982; 32344 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Emory University, 1982-1983; 32343 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Fund for Modern Courts, 1982-1983; 32342 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Aspen Institute, 1986-1989; 32341 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Society of Fellows Seminar, 1987; 32340 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Seminar Readings on Justice and Society, 1984; 32339 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Sophocles I, undated; 32338 (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Defenders Services Materials, 1988-1989; 32337 (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Aspen Institute, 1989; 32336 (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Aspen Institute, 1988-1989; 32335 (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Aspen Institute, 1977; 32334 (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - Aspen Institute Conference, 1989; 32333 (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - Articles and Other Writings, 1940s-1950s (Box 42, Folder 1-3)
  - Articles and Other Writings, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 4-5, Box 43, Folder 1-4)
  - Articles and Other Writings, 1970s (Box 43, Folder 5, Box 44, Folder 1-5, Box 45, Folder 1-4, Box 46, Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Articles and Other Writings, 1980s (Box 47, Folder 2-5, Box 50, Folder 1-4, Box 51, Folder 1-5, Box 52, Box 53, Box 54, Box 55, Box 56, Box 57, Box 58, Folder 1-2, Box 59)
  - Articles and Other Writings, 1990 (Box 58, Folder 3-4)